我记得你好像说过这玩意有瞄准系统的,托尼
I thought you said this thing had a targeting system, Tony.
我瞄不准那艘船, 情况开始有点麻烦了
Can't get a bead on that ship, and it's starting to get hairy up here.
好戏开场
Show time.
现在他们咬上咱们了
And now they got their hooks into us.
不知道是谁疯狂到向我们进攻
Don't know who's crazy enough to attack us,
但该结束战斗了, 钢铁侠
but it's time to end this, Iron Man.
你好啊, 叉骨?
What's up, Crossbones?
要不要直接投降免得你丢面子?
Want to just give up and save yourself the embarrassment?
嗯. 他们总宁愿丢面子
Hmm. They always choose embarrassment.
抓稳. 平衡翼被击中了
Hold on. Stabilizers are shot.
那么, 毛毛, 你在树旁边发现什么了?
So, fluffy, what would you find on the outside of a tree?
退后. 情况尽在掌握
Stay back. We have this under control.
差劲的行动啊, 叉骨, 竟然独自来进攻我们
B-level move, Crossbones, attacking us by yourself.
独自? 你没听说吗, 斯塔克?
Myself? Didn't you hear, Stark?
今天是团队协作日
It's bring-a-pal-to-work day.
有人受伤吗?
Anyone hurt?
该装个后视镜了, 斯塔克
Should've installed rear-view mirrors on that thing, Stark.
死神? 怎么着, 今天是海盗主题派对
Grim Reaper? What, is there a pirate theme going on here
而没人通知我?
that I didn't get the memo for?
DBC独家: 钢铁侠和美国队长正受到攻击
DBC exclusive: Iron Man and Captain America under attack.
钢铁侠!
Iron Man!
不!
No!
复仇者集结
"深入敌后"
就是这了?
This is the location?
除非我飞船上的导航仪坏了
Unless the onboard on my ship was lying.
急什么, 叉骨? 你不会坏事吧?
Why so jumpy, Crossbones? You aren't gonna blow this, are you?
我以为一切关于九头蛇的事你都感兴趣
I thought all things Hydra was your deal.
我担心的不是我自己坏事
It's not me I'm worried about.
按计划行事, 别出"惊喜"
Just stick to the plan, keep the surprises to a minimum,
这样我们还有可能成功
and we might just make this work.
SLOMO动画组
"惊喜"? 我?
Surprises? Moi?
你是负责出力的, 加把劲
You're the muscle on this team.
他可不会自己往里走
He ain't just gettin' up and walkin' in.
开门
Open up.
这点见面礼够不够让我们加入你的反派小俱乐部, 红骷髅?
This good enough to get us into your little villain club, Red Skull?
启动潜艇
Launch the sub.
潜艇? 你知道这玩意是潜艇吗?
Sub? Did you know this thing was a sub?
火山基地, 空间站, 现在是潜艇...
Volcano base, space station, sub...
有什么不同? 我们已经在这了, 笑一笑吧
What's the diff? We're here. Smile.
杀人脑, 他们这么浪费我们的时间, 我要不要杀了他们?
MODOK, shall I destroy them for wasting our time?
啥?
What?
不, 这确实是斯塔克的战甲. 咱们来看看里面装着什么
No, it's definitely Stark's armor. Let's see what's inside.
早试过了打不开. 那技术简直...太赞了
Already tried. The tech is... awesome.
想攻破可不容易
It's not going to be easy to crack.
你以为你那点科技水平能跟我这样的专家相提并论
Don't insult me by assuming you possess
简直是对我的侮辱!
anything close to my scientific expertise!
你确定它是锁着的?
You're positive that it's on lockdown?
你干嘛问我? 我长得像托尼·斯塔克吗?
Why are you asking me? Do I look like Tony Stark to you?
他给这副战甲加入了神经抵御剂
He's imbedded neuro-inhibitors into this armor!
毫无疑问是为了防范我
Undoubtedly to protect himself from my technopathic abilities.
专家您要不要个扳手啊?
Does your scientific expertise-ness need a wrench?
闭嘴! 俗话说, 条条大路
Quiet! As the saying goes, there's more than one way
通...罗马!
to crack an... egg!
这帮蠢蛋走运了, 锁定了我的战甲
These chuckleheads got lucky and locked my armor.
但这不意味着我出局了
But that doesn't mean I'm out of the game.
干嘛? 我警告过他的
What? I warned him.
把这死铁罐弄到我的实验室去
Bring this iron carcass to my lab.
我要把他的壳碎成一片一片的
I will rip that armor apart piece by piece.
看来你们确实有一手
It appears you are competent after all.
我们的团体里兴许有你们一席之地
There might be room for you in our cabal.
成了
Score.
一直以来, 复仇者靠团结一心来战胜
It is said that, together, the Avengers can face threats
单个英雄没法战胜的威胁
no single hero can.
那么...
Then...
只有我们, 他们最强大的敌人, 也合作
it is only fitting that we, their greatest foes, work together
才能消灭他们
in order to destroy them.
这比我们想象的宏大多了
This is bigger than we could have ever imagined.
- 是啊, 而且我可是挺敢想的 - 震撼人心, 是不是?
- Yeah, and I can imagine pretty big. - Breathtaking, is it not?
我们要建立一支世人前所未见的大军
We are building an army unlike any the world has ever seen.
你有多少兵力?
How many troops you have?
更重要的是, 你拿什么付钱给他们?
More importantly, what are you paying them?
咱们下一个行动的时间地点是什么?
What's the date and location of our next target?
这艘潜艇的动力源是什么?
What kind of power source does this sub use?
这些问题对于小步兵来说太深奥了
These are sophisticated questions for mere foot-soldiers.
- 小步兵? - 我们可是搞定了钢铁侠的
- Foot-soldiers? - We took down Iron Man.
而你, 据我们所知, 没做到过
Which, when we last checked, you failed to do. [hissing]
红骷髅, 这两个血袋是谁?
Skull, who are these blood sacks?
我们不喜欢他们的味道
We don't like their smell.
吸血鬼? 你船上有吸血鬼?
Vampires? You have vampires on board?
起开, 绿牙怪
Step off, green teeth.
死神, 你干什么?
Reaper, what are you doing?
我们可不喜欢吸血鬼, 叉骨, 记得吗?
We don't like vampires, Bones. Remember?
他们能控制被咬的人. 这对咱们不妙
They can take over anyone they bite. Not good for us.
- 怎么... - 杀人脑的安全措施
- How the... - MODOK's security protocols
抑制船上所有的科技设备
dampen all tech aboard this sub.
这让大家都能好好说话
It keeps everyone on their best behavior.
成员之间再有冲突的话后果严重
Further hostilities between members will be dealt with severely.
德古拉会知道这等荒谬之事的
Dracula will hear of this outrage.
德古拉? 他也参与了?
Dracula? Part of the cabal?
你们根本想不到我们集结了多少力量
You have no idea of the power we've amassed.
客人到了
Our guest has arrived.
客人? 我们在水下2000英尺. 谁会...
Guest? We've gotta be 2,000 feet down by now. Who...
全舰注意, 海煞到了
All stations, Attuma's here.
海煞?
Attuma?
红骷髅, 亚特兰蒂斯霸主海煞业已实现他的承诺
Skull, Attuma, Warlord of Atlantis, has done as he has promised.
我已拿到武器
He has the weapon.
现在让我们来看看你能否做到你说过的事
Now let us see if you can do as you claim.
来, 霸主. 你会看到
Come, warlord. You will see that everything
我们谋划的一切都顺利进行着
we agreed to is going as planned.
照顾好他的部下
See to his soldiers.
如果那武器真有海煞说的威力
If the weapon does what lord Attuma promises,
咱们对阵复仇者即刻必胜
our war against the Avengers ends today.
你的技术没有我破解不了的
There's no technology that you can build that I cannot undo.
我来了, 斯塔克
I'm coming for you, Stark.
一具空壳! 我们被骗了!
An empty shell! We were tricked!
我们饿了. 拿吃的来!
We are hungry. Bring us food!
你是在指使自名死神的人
You didn't just tell a guy who calls himself the Grim Reaper
伺候你吃饭, 是吗?
to bring you food, did you?
你们想吃点啥? 肘击三明治怎么样?
What would you fellas like? A knuckle sandwich?
- 这么说你看够了? - 哦,是的. 早看够了
- You've seen enough, then? - Oh, yeah. I've seen enough.
死神和叉骨背叛了我们. 立刻把他们带到我的实验室!
Reaper and Crossbones betrayed us. Bring them to my lab immediately!
嘿, 斯塔克也骗了我们, 杀人脑
Hey, Stark tricked us, too, MODOK.
是啊, 我们怎么会知道他不在他的战甲里?
Yeah, how were we supposed to know that Stark wasn't in his armor?
哦, 大概因为我就是斯塔克
Oh, because I am Stark.
安全漏洞!
Security breach!
托尼·斯塔克和史蒂夫·罗杰斯混进来了!
Tony Stark and Steve Rogers have infiltrated our ranks!
所有人手速至港舱!
All hands to the aqua port!
好家伙. 你就不能在他们拉下咱们的面具前出招吗?
Great. Couldn't you have done that before they pulled off our masks?
还说我? 你就不能好好地让他们抓住你么
Me? You practically did everything but surrender.
你之前电击杀人脑那一出怎么算?
What was that shock stunt you pulled on MODOK earlier?
那叫假戏真做
It's called establishing credibility.
托尼·斯塔克永远不会让任杀人脑碰他的战甲
Tony Stark would never let MODOK touch his armor
除非先扇他个20000瓦的钢铁耳光
without giving him a 20,000 volt iron slap.
我知道你喜欢角色扮演, 托尼
I know you're enjoying the role-playing thing, Tony,
但我们得结束游戏了
but we gotta put an end to this game.
目标确认. 锁定坐标
Targets identified. Lock on to these coordinates.
复仇者, 集结!
Avengers, assemble!
等等. 我的线路有问题. 复仇者, 集结!
Hold up. My line. Avengers, assemble!
身份卡的信号被阻拦了
Something's blocking the card's transmission.
好吧, 我来召回我的战甲, 让钢铁侠来...
Okay, I'll just summon my armor, and it'll be Iron Man to the...
杀人脑的电子抑制器. 他锁定了我们的设备
MODOK dampeners. He's targeted our tech.
敌方位置?
What's the location on the hostiles?
12点, 9点, 5点方向
12 o'clock, 9 o'clock, 5 o'clock.
好的, 一种选择, 我们从港舱这里撤到水中
Okay, option 1, we escape through the aqua port into the water.
另一种, 一路打进红骷髅的指挥中心
Options 2, fight our way through to the Skull's communication center,
- 从那召集复仇者 - 或者另一个超赞的选项
- and call the Avengers from there. - Or option "awesome",
我黑了杀人脑的追踪系统
I hack into MODOK's tracking systems,
再溜进他的实验室, 拿回我的战甲
sneak into his lab, and get my armor back.
不, 托尼, 我们没时间了
No, Tony, we don't have time.
对于托尼·斯塔克来说永远有时间...
There's always time when you're Tony Stark...
杀人脑! 他们在哪?
MODOK! Where are they?
我追踪不到
I can't trace them.
斯塔克肯定黑了我的系统!
Stark must have hacked my systems!
真没用. 搜索全舰!
Pathetic. Search the sub!
你们亚特兰蒂斯人, 检查舰外区域
You, Atlantians, check outside the ship.
我的士兵们只听命于我, 红骷髅
My warriors only take orders from me, Skull.
那就命令他们, 海煞
Then tell them, Attuma.
注意你的口气, 骷髅
I would watch your tongue, skeleton.
你这艘小锡盒可是漂在我的海里
This tin box of yours is floating in my ocean.
复仇者也在你的海里
Your ocean has Avengers in it.
士兵们, 巡查水域
Warriors, search the waters.
我不能冒险让复仇者窃取我们的成果
I will not risk the Avengers stealing our prize.
看起来他们的小团体并没那么团结
Looks like their little cabal ain't the well-oiled machine
- 红骷髅只是在放空话 - 似曾相识啊
- Skull made it out to be. - Sounds familiar.
什么? 你什么意思?
What? What are you saying?
我差点没能及时把你弄进这架飞机里. 你让我们置身...
I barely got you inside this air shaft in time. You put us in...
你说什... 我糊弄了杀人脑!
What are you... I blinded MODOK!
你是想下去游泳还是大摇大摆地晃去指挥中心?
You wanted to go down swimming or swinging?
就我看来, 这仍是我们仅有的两个选择
As far as I can tell, those are still our only two options.
我就知道这计划是胡扯
I knew this plan was a load of hooey.
红骷髅肯定已经打败罗杰斯了
Skull must have put the knuckle down on Rogers.
同志们, 我们有大麻烦了
People, we got trouble with a capital T.
- 史上最差的队长模仿秀, 鹰眼 -  啥? 队长绝对是这么说话的
- Worst cap impression ever, Hawkeye. - What? Cap totally talks like that.
猎鹰, 他们的...
Falcon, what's the status on their...
啊, "地点"的老式用语怎么说?
uh, what's the old-timey lingo for "location?"
他们的信号一直在移动. 在某种水下运输工具上
Their signal went on the move. Some kind of underwater transport.
我在哪都找不到
I can't find it anywhere.
你们本应派我去. 我是专业间谍, 记得吗?
You should have sent me. I'm the professional spy, remember?
呃, 死神和叉骨的衣服你穿不合适
Ah, Reaper's and Crossbones' costumes wouldn't fit you.
我要联络神盾来找找别的办法追踪他们
I'm gonna hook up with S.H.I.E.L.D. to try and track them another way.
或者我们可以直接问他们. 用浩克的方式
Or we could just ask them. Hulk style. [Hulk growls]
我喜欢这主意
I like that idea. [knuckles crack]
杀人脑的电子抑制器多半是
MODOK's power dampener is most likely activated
靠他脑门上的黑盒子维持的
by the black box on his forehead.
我们关闭它, 然后我就能重新激活的我战甲
We shut it down, and I can reactivate my armor.
呃, 又来了
Ugh, not that again.
红骷髅, 杀人脑, 海煞都在找我们
We got Skull, MODOK, and Attuma out looking for us.
我们需要的是发信号联络其他队员
We need to get a signal back to the rest of the team,
而且即便如此... 等等. 那是什么?
and even up these... Hold on. What is that?
那是海煞带来的东西
That's the thing Attuma brought on board.
红骷髅说过一些关于即刻必胜的话
Skull said something about ending the war today.
从这些能量数据来看, 他应该在谋划什么
From the looks of those power signatures, he may be on to something.
这群亚特兰提斯人把整个潜艇都熏臭了
These Atlantians are stinkin' up the whole sub.
- 哈? - 我们找到他们了!
- Huh? - We found them!
没时间逃跑了, 改战斗吧
No time for flight, moving to the fight option.
你知道, 这本可以容易得多, 如果我有战甲
You know, this would be a lot easier if I had my armor
你有盾牌...
and you had your shield...
浩克也在的话
and we had the Hulk.
你的思路不对, 托尼
You're not looking at this in the right way, Tony.
首先, 问问你自己
Step one, ask yourself,
"一个科学天才会怎么做?" 其次...
"what would a science whiz do?" Step two...
我来吸引目标, 让天才来施展才华
I distract the target and let the whiz do his biz.
不是我, 是斯塔克! 是他干的!
It's not me, it's Stark! He's doing it!
- 然后, 我们享受这副光景 - 还真奏效了
- Step three, we enjoy the view. - That actually worked.
因为, 我的朋友... 这是...
Because that, my friend... was a... [vampires hissing]
没想到我会乐意见到吸血鬼
Never thought I'd be happy to see vampires,
不过他们确实让我省了听你的长篇大论
but they're saving me from one of your "lectures."
- 史蒂夫, 屏住呼吸. - 不! 那样行不通!
- Steve, hold your breath. - No! That's not a plan!
- 他们逃了! - 什么样的技术奇才会找不到
- They must have escaped! - What kind of a technopath can't find
两个凡人, 还是在一艘他完全掌控的潜艇上?
two humans on a submarine that he has complete control over?
他们会被抓住的, 红骷髅
They will be captured soon enough, Skull.
他们不可能永远躲开我
They cannot escape me forever.
再说, 斯塔克没有战甲就毫无力量. 就像你
Besides, Stark is powerless without his armor. Just like you.
别逼我, 杀人脑. 我们的团体里没什么人是不可替代的
Do not push me, MODOK. No one's place in this cabal is secure.
- 长官, 三叉戟准备好了 - 终于
- Sir, the Trident is free. - At last.
哦, 听上去可不像好事
Oh, I don't like the sounds of that.
我们得阻止他们. 而且这次
We have to stop them. And this time,
我们不能再放他们一马了
we're not marching in and making it up as we go.
听着, 我承认
Look, I admit it,
如果你没想到这个渗透计划
if you hadn't come up with this plan to infiltrate the cabal,
我们根本不可能知道这事有多严重
we never would have learned how serious this was getting.
- 谢了, 但... - 但没有我的战甲
- Thanks, but... - But with my armor gone,
我只能见机行事
all I can do is improvise.
史蒂夫, 即便没有盾牌, 你仍旧是美国队长
Steve, even without your shield, you're still Captain America.
- 可没有战甲, 我只是... - 托尼·斯塔克! 独一无二的托尼·斯塔克
- Without my armor, I'm just... - Tony Stark! The Tony Stark.
亿万富翁, 天生奇才
Billionaire genius.
你大概能排进全世界最聪明的人的前三名
You're probably one of the three smartest men in the entire world.
你要多强悍有多强悍
You're as tough as they come. You invented hardcore.
有你在我们这边是复仇者的幸运
The Avengers are lucky you're on our side.
真的? 你还认识两个比我聪明的人?
Really? You know two people smarter than me?
你就不能乖乖接受表扬?
Can't you just take a compliment?
海神三叉戟
Neptune's Trident.
神祇之武器! 大海之神力!
Weapon of the gods! The power of the ocean itself!
复仇者将会失败
The Avengers shall fall,
世上所有国家都将敬畏我们
and all the nations of the world shall tremble before us.
- 好了, 我有个计划 - 是什么?
- Okay, I've got a plan. - You do? What is it?
- 被抓 - 等等!
- Get caught. - Wait!
嘿! 谁知道我上哪能找到一个巨型沙拉叉?
Hey! Anyone know where I can get a giant salad fork?
你知道计划两字怎么写吗?
Do you even know what a plan is?
那么, 托尼·斯塔克和史蒂夫·罗杰斯
So, Tony Stark and Steve Rogers.
我早该知道斯塔克会如此冲动行事
I should have guessed that Stark would do something as impulsive as this.
但你, 队长, 真让我意外
But you, Captain, surprise me.
在这没有了盾牌和战甲的保护
Here without shields or armor to protect you.
你们该吃点苦头了
Now you will both pay for it.
我不觉得这计划有什么好的, 托尼
Not sure I'm seeing the brilliance of this plan yet, Tony.
你只是没仔细看, 史蒂夫
You just aren't looking close enough, Steve.
是时候看看海神三叉戟是否真如传说一般强大了
Time to find out if the Trident of Neptune lives up to its legend.
你干什么?
What are you doing?
你会毁掉船体的!
You'll rupture the hull!
是真的! 控制海洋的力量!
It's true! The power to command the sea!
喔. 这招在拉斯维加斯肯定受欢迎
Wow. You'll really kill them in Vegas.
你还在嘲笑我们, 斯塔克
You mock us, Stark.
有了三叉戟, 我们就能够把水进行武器化
With this Trident, we have just weaponized water.
四分之三的地球已在我们的掌控之中
Three quarters of the Earth is now the cabal's to control.
- 哈德逊河可以让给你 - 把他嘴塞上
- You can have the Hudson river. - Put a sock in it.
说真的, 你这张嘴就没有消停的时候?
Seriously, is there an OFF-switch on that mouth?
红骷髅刚告诉你他要控制整个世界
Skull just told you that he's going to hold the entire world hostage,
- 而你就顾着讲笑话? - 你才是个笑话, 罗杰斯
- and you're cracking jokes? - You're the only joke here, Rogers.
你们超级士兵都一个样. 坐享聪明人的成果
You super-soldiers are all alike. Living off the work of smarter men.
举个例子, 杀人脑取得了我的战甲
Case in point, MODOK, he took my armor.
红骷髅要做的就只是穿上它. 而再看看现在他俩谁手里有三叉戟
All Skull did was put it on. And now look who's holding the Trident.
红骷髅! 你最好别打算独占三叉戟!
Skull! You don't plan on keeping the Trident for only yourself!
它不能同时受多人支配
Only one can wield it at a time.
我们的协定可不是如此. 把它还给我
That was not our agreement. You released it for Attuma.
它的力量来自海洋. 我才是它的正当主人
Its power is derived from the ocean. I am its rightful lord!
不! 是我抓住他们俩的! 我才有资格毁灭他们!
No! I caught these two! They're mine to destroy!
你敢? 我是一位君主!
You dare? I am a king!
你不过是红骷髅的哈巴狗
You are nothing but the Skull's lapdog.
君主? 哈! 你就是个鱼贩子
King? Ha! You're a fishmonger.
我杀人脑是科技宗师!
I am MODOK, Master of science!
够了! 你们看不出他们是想分化我们吗?
Enough! Don't' you see they seek to divide us?
他们把你们当猴耍!
They are playing you for fools!
我受够你的羞辱了, 钢铁红骷髅!
I have had enough of your insults, Iron Skull!
嘿, 蠢人脑! 你脑门上有东西
Hey, MODork! You've got something on your forehead.
咱们成功了?
We all good now?
马上, 十秒之内
We will be. In about 10 seconds.
- 拖住他! - 没问题
- Stall him! - Consider him stalled.
我这次没那么容易输给你们了, 复仇者. 什么?
Not this time, Avengers. What?
我还能说什么呢? 我就是穿衣有品
What can I say? I dress to impress.
你已经无法阻止我了, 斯塔克
You're too late to stop me, Stark.
这次连你的战甲都救不了你
Not even your armor can save you from this.
托尼!
Tony!
红骷髅!
Skull!
你太保守了, 红骷髅
You think too small, Skull.
海煞来让你见识真正的七海之力!
Attuma shall show you the true power of the seven seas!
不...
No...
托尼, 该你上了
Tony, do your thing.
搞定
Done.
不
No.
蠢货! 你们知道你们干了什么吗?
You fools! Do you realize what you've done?
阻止你控制世界呗
Yeah, stopped you from ruling the world.
你们释放了海神之力!
You've unleashed the power of Neptune!
你们激怒了海洋本身!
You have angered the ocean itself!
弃船!
Abandon ship!
史蒂夫, 抓紧
Steve, hold on.
漩涡在把我们往下拽
The force of the whirlpool is dragging us down.
史蒂夫, 对不起. 我的战甲, 支持不住了
Steve, I'm sorry. My armor, it's not enough.
- 别担心! - 为什么? 现在是该担心的时候啊
- Don't worry! - Why not? Seems like a good time.
杀人脑的电子抑制器停摆时, 我呼叫了他们
When MODOK's power dampener was destroyed, I called them.
多谢你接住我们, 鹰眼
Thanks for the lift, Hawkeye.
妥妥的, 小子
No problem, Bucko.
我待会再解释. 红骷髅他们呢?
I'll explain later. Where's the cabal?
水下20000里格, 重新审视他们的搭档关系呢
20,000 leagues under the sea, reevaluating their partnership.
比起战胜那个邪恶小团体
I'm surprised you guys survived each other,
我更惊讶于你们居然忍得了彼此
much less the cabal.
我发现有时候依计划行事也挺好的
I recently learned it doesn't hurt to have a plan sometimes.
哦, 这有点讽刺
Oh, now, isn't that ironic?
因为我反而发现有时候就该随心所致, 临场发挥
'Cause I learned that sometimes you should just follow your gut.
那现在... 你俩抱一个还是怎么?
So, like... are you pals gonna hug now, or what?
你为什么还穿着我的制服?
Why are you still wearing my uniform?
欢迎关注@Slomo-Lu小鱼
Weibo.com/2092509395
翻译 张小堂
特效 Lu小鱼
校对 少数派memetics
压制 Lu小鱼
时间轴 Lu小鱼